mtbproject.com 2019-05-07

# Adventure Projects Privacy Policy

**ADVENTURE PROJECTS, INC.**

Adventure Projects (“Company,” “we” or “us”) understands the importance of privacy. This Policy applies to the Adventure Projects websites (“Sites”) and mobile applications (“Apps”) that display or link to this Privacy Policy (the “Policy”). In this Policy we explain how we collect, use and disclose the information that we obtain via our Sites and Apps, including the services available through the Sites and Apps (collectively, the “ **Services** ” includes the Sites and Apps, as well as the services available through them).

By accessing or using the Services, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Policy. Your use of the Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes, available at <https://www.adventureprojects.net/terms> and incorporated by reference into this Policy.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**  
We may collect information about you directly from you, as well as automatically through your use of our Services.

**_Account Registration_** _.  _You may browse certain areas of our Site and use some our Services without registering. However, to access certain Services, we require you to create an account with us or log in through Facebook. To sign up for an account with us, you must submit your email and in some cases your name; we may send you an activation link to confirm your registration. If you login through Facebook, you must grant us permission to access your email address, and public profile information. We may access your Facebook data at any time even if you are not using Facebook. After you have registered with us or logged in through Facebook, we may also collect additional optional information from you, including any information you add to your account profile, including your full name, zip/postal code, city and state, interests, a profile picture, and other information. In addition, once registered through one of our Sites or Apps, you may use the same account information to access our other Sites and Apps.

**_Public Content_** _.  _We collect information about the content you post to the Services. Further, any text, images, photos, audio, video, location data, and all other forms of data or communication and other content you post to the Services will be publically viewable. We may display this content on the Services, and further distribute it to a wider audience through third party sites and services.

**_Other Information_**. In addition, we may offer surveys, contests and promotions. If you participate, we will collect additional information from you, which could include additional personal information.

**_Information We Collect Automatically_** _._ We may automatically collect and store information related to you and your use of the Services through cookies, web beacons, log files, java script and other technologies, such as your browser type; IP address; unique device identifier; geo-location; referring URL (webpage that led you to our Site); browser language; the pages you view and links you click on the Services; the date and time of your visit; the length of time you spend on the Services; your domain name; your operating system; visit our Site and or use our Services; and your location information. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you, including, where applicable, your user name, name, and other personal information. Please see the section “Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” below for more information. 

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION**

We use your information, including your personal information, for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Services, to respond to your inquiries, and for other customer service purposes. 
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization, and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site or our Services. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising our Services on third party websites, and in advertising third party products and services on our Site. 
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may use your information, such as your email address, to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you. 
  * To better understand how users access and use our Site and Services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site and Services, respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes (such as analyzing and composing reports on trends, which may be sold to third parties). 

**HOW WE DISCLOSE INFORMATION**

As noted above, your user name and any information that you post to our Services, is publically available. You can also choose to share your location, activities, comments on trails and conditions, and other information with other users. In addition, we may disclose or share the information we collect, including personal information as follows:

  * **_Service Providers_**. We may outsource some of our technical and customer support, functions and other services to third party third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf. We may share information from or about you with them so that they can perform their services. 
  * **_Affiliates_**. We may disclose the information we collect from you to our affiliates, including our parent company REI Co-op who will use and handle your information in accordance with its own [privacy policy](http://www.rei.com/help/privacy-policy.html). Our affiliates (including REI Co-op) may, for example, use your information to send you informational or promotional offers, as well as for other purposes consistent with their privacy policy. In addition, certain user content from our Site or App, may be shared on our affiliate’s websites. 
  * **_Partners_**. We have a relationship with the International Mountain Bike Alliance (“IMBA”), and may share name, email and zip code with IMBA. **You may opt out of this sharing** by logging in to your account and changing your communications preferences; however, opting out will not affect any information we have already shared with IMBA. In addition, if you participate in a contest or promotion offered by us, we may share your information with the sponsor of such contest or promotion; we will notify you of this at the time you choose to participate, and you can choose not to permit the sharing by not participating in the contest or promotion. 
  * **_In Response to Legal Process_**. We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a subpoena. 
  * **_To Protect Us and Others_**. We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation or arbitration. 
  * **_Business Transfers_**. If we are acquired by or merge with another company, if all or substantially all of our assets or transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the acquiring company. 
  * **_Aggregate and De-Identified Information_**. We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes, for a fee. 

**Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms**

We and our third party service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Services. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you (and our third party service providers may do so on our behalf). Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies), or the section below (e.g., by opting out of certain ad networks).

**_Cookies_**. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site and Service. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function. 

**_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies_** **.** Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages or in emails. We may use clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Site usage. We or our service providers may also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed and track whether our emails are forwarded.

**_Third-party Analytics_** **.** We use third party analytics tools, including Google Analytics, to collect, monitor and analyze Site and App information, in order to improve functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor the Services to our users’ needs. Accordingly, usage data is shared with Google, which has its own [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html?rd=2) addressing how it uses such information. We encourage you to review this privacy policy to understand how Google uses such information.

**ADVERTISING**

We use third parties such as network advertisers to display advertisements on our Site, to assist us in displaying advertisements on third party websites, and to evaluate the success of our advertising campaigns. For example, we work with [Facebook Ads](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads) to display ads on Facebook, and [Google Ads](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) to display ads on other third party sites. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to our Site as well as other websites. These third parties may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. Their use of cookies and other technologies, and the information they collect, are governed by their own privacy policies, not this one. We may provide these third-parties with information about your usage of our Site and our services.

You may opt-out of receiving ads that are based upon your visits to multiple third party websites from certain third-party ad networks (including Facebook and Google), which are operated by members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). For more information regarding this practice by NAI members and DAA members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including how to opt-out of participating third-party ad networks, please visit their respective websites: [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) (NAI) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (DAA).

**COMMUNICATIONS FROM US  
**We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you, about Company and the Services, and, from time-to-time, about third party products and offers we think may interest you. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the e-mail, or by logging in to your Company account and changing your email preferences. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving promotional emails from us, we may still send you e-mails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to request a list of third parties to whom we have disclosed personally identifiable information about you for their own direct marketing purposes, please contact us at admin@adventureprojects.net. You may make one request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. Please allow up to thirty (30) days for a response. Also, as noted in the Partners section of the Disclosure section above, you may control whether were share your information with our partner IMBA.

**User Generated Content**

As noted, you can post content to our Services, including your comments, reviews, pictures, and any other information. If you post such content, all of the information that you post may be available to other users of Services and may also be distributed on third party sites. Your posting may become public and Company cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy. In addition, other users may be able to identify you, or associate you with your user account if you include personal information in your Public Content.

**Plug-ins and Social Media Widgets**

Our Services may include social media features and widgets, such as the Facebook “Like” button and the “Share this” button, as well as other interactive mini-programs that run on our Services and enable certain features to work (e.g., blogs and comments). These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site or viewing through the Services, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly and for purposes. These features are displayed on our Services, but are hosted by third parties, and are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them

**Third-Party Links**

Our Services may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third party websites.

**DATA RETENTION AND ACCOUNT TERMINATION**  
If you terminate your account, we will remove your name and email address from our public servers but  **will not remove or delete any public content from the Services**. Please note that we may maintain this information for a period of time as part of our business records, and this information may also exist in backup storage even after it has been removed from our active databases. You can request that your account be terminated by contacting us at admin@adventureprojects.net.

**Access To My Personal Information**

You may modify personal information that you have submitted by logging into your account and updating your profile information. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site for a period of time, and we may maintain copies of such information in our business records.

**CHILDREN**  
The Services are intended for general audiences and not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child has provided us with personal information we will take steps to securely delete such information.

**SECURITY**  
We have implemented safeguards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet or via mobile device, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

**INTERNATIONAL USERS**

Any information we collect from you will be transferred to the United States, and may be transferred to other jurisdictions where we have operations, affiliates or services provides. The laws in these jurisdictions may not provide equivalent privacy protection as the laws of your home jurisdiction. By using the Services you are expressly consenting to the transfer of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**MODIFICATIONS TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
We may revise this Policy from time to time. The most current version of the Policy will govern our use of your information. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will endeavor to notify you by email or by posting a notice on the Services prior to the effective date of the changes. By continuing to access or use the Services after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Policy.

This Privacy Policy was Last Updated on August 20, 2015.
